Abbas Tolgay Yılmaz

software engineer, artist, design-thinker

tolgay@atyilmaz.com +491709360629 Hamburg, Germany

SUMMARY

hello, I'm Tolgay

over the last 4 years I have involved in several projects as a software engineer.

lately, building open-sourced projects at the intersection of social design, technology, arts, activism, politics, economics and psychology.

I am a romantic person, with an utmost passion for changing the world with creative instrumentalisation of technology.

TRAITS

- -collaborative, inclusive and proactive mindset.
- web and recently blockchain and designthinking,
- backend development with Java 8+/SpringBoot and Elixir/Phoenix
- -frontend development with react.js/grommet and also vanilla Javascript, HTML, Ajax, Bootstrap, Tailwind
- comfortable working with cloud, Docker, Unix systems, Postgres, MySQL, git, continuous deployment, event-driven systems

EXPERIENCE

founder

stateful.art | Aug 2021 - Present

- participating in ideation, design and community building
- evaluation, integration & development of NFT and DAOs
- collaboration and partnership with other open projects
- writing proposals for grants, and preparing pitch decks
- using Solidity/Hardhat

founder

futurema.de | 2020 - Present

- developed a demand-aware framework proposal eventually experiment the potential impact of "expression of demand".
- developed a web app for requesting a flexible online concert ticket via Spotify login, through artist's profile.

software engineer / backend

Vattenfall Energy Trading GmbH | 2019

- contributed to an agile project team in coding, reviews
- contributed to a project, that is to establish data aggregation between wind parks and energy markets.
- used SpringBoot, Cassandra and Hazelcast

software engineer / full-stack

Element Insurance AG | 2018 - 2019

- contributed to an agile project team in coding, reviews
- used Java8, SpringBoot, React, AWS (s3, cognito, dynamoDB), Docker, Terraform

software engineer full-stack (consultant)

Technology Development Group | 2017 - 2018

- developed a web app that reverse engineered SOAPUI for our client, Türkiye Is Bankasi.
- it was used for quality assurance in pre-prod versions of banking services, including requests in SOAP and JSON
- used Java8, SpringBoot, Javascript, AJAX, Thymeleaf, Grafana, LDAP with Spring Security, MySQL

software engineer / backend

Ericsson | 2017

- supported development of internal charging tool
- prepared migration scripts for unbundling
- used Java 7, JBOSS, Camel Framework

integration and test engineer (consultant)

Ericsson | 2014-2016

- worked in business operations department for clie
- script development with Oracle PL/SQL to automate configuration review processes.

LANGUAGES

Turkish native

English professional

German A2.2 < ... < B1

LIVELY-IMPULSE

making artworks <u>in visual</u> and <u>audio</u> forms, playing chess and table tennis.





EDUCATION

Istanbul Bilgi University -- dropped @ thesis

MA Information and Technology Law | 2016 - 2018

• enrolled in master classes on digital crimes, ethics, forensics, regulations.

Izmir Institute of Technology

BS Computer Engineering | 2008 - 2014

- theory of computation, functional and object-oriented programming, operating systems, UML, database modeling, networks and architecture, computer vision, software engineering (track)
- as thesis project, used leap motion device and paper board to bypass the need for eye-monitor coordination.

Aarhus University

Erasmus Exchange Programme | Spring, 2011

 enrolled in the classes of augmented reality, technical project management and interactive technology design.

HACKATHONS

nftvisionhack - Rarible, IPFS stack Remote, 2021

Ford Open XC Hackathon Istanbul, 2017

Hack for Culture - British Council, Audience Finder and TTGV Istanbul, 2016

Pepsico Insight Challenge - Nielsen Istanbul, 2015

ING Bank Hackathon Istanbul, 2015



